James Peden



Key Skills:

Motion Graphics Video Editing Visual effects Compositing Rotoscoping Character animation Sound editing Colour grading On-location filming

Software/Plugins:

Adobe suite

- After effects
- Premiere pro
- Audition
- Illustrator
- Photoshop Mocha AE Maxon one plugins

Education:

BA (Hons) Film Making & Creative Media (2011 - 2014)University of the West of England

Profile:

I currently work in a fast paced B2B marketing agency focused on the tech sector. Here I have been creating a range of motion graphic content, live action, animations, audio and podcasts, live action, animations, audio and podcasts for a variety of global clients. I always approach the projects with a client focussed view to ensure I really understand their needs and how I can elevate the work whilst highlighting the core values they hold.

I have worked across a range of industries including; B2B & B2C marketing, events, entertainment, technology and education. marketing, events, entertainment, technology and education. I have created content to work across a variety of platforms, for example: broadcast, social media and websites. My experience ranges from freelance work to small in-house production teams all the way up to large agency environments. I adapt to new surroundings easily and enjoy meeting and getting to know new people.

I am a dedicated team member, and I love the work I do. I value collaboration with my colleagues and I'm always willing to lend a hand and share knowledge. I have a passion for seeing projects through the three C's: conception, creation and completion and I gain a great sense of satisfaction from putting out good work. Both during projects and in my free time I constantly challenge my free time. I constantly challenge myself to develop my skill set as well as refining my working processes. I consistently create work that not only meets the brief but does so in a fun and entertaining way. I feel my background in filmmaking has given me a strong understanding of storytelling, which allows me to ensure the purpose of the project is not lost in aesthetics of the designs.

Experience:

Motion designer, Revere 04/2022 - 07/2023

Each project is unique and has its challenges, I am responsible for creating bespoke animations, typographical animations, rotoscoping, motion tracking, as well on location filming and editing. I worked across multiple campaigns for a variety of clients to produce a range of high quality motion content, live action, animation, audio and podcasts that gets published across socials, websites and client channels.

Video editor, Moonbug 03/2020 - 08/2022

Editing a range of video content for Moonbug Entertainment. This has consisted of editing a range of content which would be distributed across platforms such as Broadcast and Social platforms. I worked on processing rushes, adding SFX, balancing audio levels, colour grading, compositing green screen elements, animating subtitles and localising content across multiple languages.

Video editor & Motion graphic designer, Lobster Pictures 01/2018 - 09/2019

Creating broadcast quality time-lapse videos, produced short films and a variety of motion graphic content. each project bringing with it the clients unique brand guidelines. I liaised directly with clients to ensure the projects meet their expectations and budget.

Motion graphic designer, Sounds Commercial 05/2017 - 01/2018

Planning and creating all of the motion graphic elements to meet clients briefs. Consisting of designing award / conference opening and closing animations, animating logos, stings, lower thirds and infographics. I also assisted on shoots and edits as required. I worked closely with the wider team to ensure each client's brand guidelines are adhered to across all deliverables.

Junior motion graphics designer, Three 06/2016 - 05/2017

Taking a project from the initial idea through storyboarding to completion experimenting with creative ways to portray the narrative. Working individually and when required collaboratively to create effective, informative, and on-brand videos for multi-channel distribution.

Wateraid - Motion Graphic Designer 09/15 - 01/16

Oxford University - Video Production Intern 10/14 - 03/15

University of the West of England - Motion Graphics 09/14

References:

Revere

Alex Young - Lead motion designer Alex.young@thisisrevere.com

Rintje Barnes - Executive Creative Director rintje.barnes@thisisrevere.com

Lobster Pictures

Paul McKelvie - Video Producer mail@paulmckelvie.co.uk